Okay so now we're going to prepare the bat for the wheel.
And attach the clay to the bat so that we can start centering.
First thing we're going to do is look on the bottom of the bat and we have these two sets of little holes here.
And they're going to correspond with these pins that are on the wheel.
We're going to attach this.
Now it's very important to have the right surface to stick the clay to, and having a pot, there's obviously been a pot that's been thrown on here.
And there's still some nice wet clay on there.
This would be a great surface to attach the clay to, however, we often don't have that.
So I'm just going to trim this off, and show you what you need to do to prepare the bat.
The bat needs to be a little bit wet, but not too wet.
If it's too wet the clay will just simply slide off it and you won't get it to adhere to the bat.
If the bat's dry it also won't stick.
So what we do is we take a sponge and we just wet down the bat.
And then I take my towel here and I just run it across.
And now you can see we have a nice surface to attach the clay to, we also have created a little ring here so that when we lay the clay down on the bat we can see it's almost centered just sitting there.
Attaching the clay we want to take the clay in both hands, line it up, and smack it down.
Okay so now we're prepared the bat and attached the clay.
The next step is centering our lump of clay to make our plant pot.
And we will be doing that next.